Guide to the National Education Association-Councils records, 1849-1983 NEA1004.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Council of National Organizations on Children and Youth, 1929-1983; 1962-1978; Series 2; 8.25 Linear Feet
  - Federal Quarterly Reports, 1967-1973; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 13)
    This folder is subject to review by Special Collections staff before being made available for research. As researchers request materials, a review of the documents will take place. Staff will remove any documents with social security numbers, employee numbers or other sensitive identifying information. Any document found including this information is closed for 90 years from date of creation, or until verifiable proof of a person's death is given. After these documents are removed the folder will be available for research. In some cases, items may be photocopied and redacted. The redacted copy will then be placed in the publicly available folder. All other materials in a folder will be freely available for immediate use and will be marked as having been reviewed by Special Collections staff. After folders have been reviewed using these procedures and the confidential materials have been removed, the restriction shall be lifted.
  - Finance Committee, 1973-1974; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 14)
  - Finances, 1973; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 15)
  - Financial Statements, December 1977; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 16)
  - Financial Statements, June 1978; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 17)
  - Financial Statements-NCCY, 1962-1966; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 18)
  - Financial Statements-NCCY, 1967-1970; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 19)
  - Financial Statements-NCCY, 1971; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 20)
  - Financial Statements-NCCY, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 21)
  - Financial Statements-NCCY, June 1974; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 22)
  - Fleming, Virginia, 1976; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 23)
    Fleming, Virginia
  - "Focus '79", 1979; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 24)
  - "Focus: A Year in Review", 1978; Series 2 (Box 1577, Folder 25)
  - "Focus on Children and Youth", June 1974-August 1975; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 1)
  - "Focus on Children and Youth", September 1975-December 1976; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 2)
  - "Focus on Children and Youth", February 1977-September 1978; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 3)
  - "Focus on Children and Youth", October 1978-May 1980; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 4)
  - "Follow up by Girl Scouts of the USA", 1961; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 5)
  - Follow Up Committee (CNOCY), 1971-1972; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 6)
  - Foster Care/Adoption Cluster, 1975-1976; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 7)
  - Full Members, September 1979; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 8)
  - Full Voting Members, 1979; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 9)
  - Full Voting Members-Minutes, April 1978; Series 2 (Box 1578, Folder 10)
  - Golden Anniversary White House Conference-Audit Report, 1960; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 1)
  - Golden Anniversary White House Conference-Certificate of Exemption, 1959; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 2)
  - Golden Anniversary White House Conference-Change of Name, 1951-1961; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 3)
  - Golden Anniversary White House Conference-Minute Book, 1959-1961; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 4)
  - Grant Proposal, 1972-1983; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 5)
  - Halpert, Stuart, 1976-1977; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 6)
    Halpert, Stuart
  - Halpert, Stuart, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 7)
  - Historical Log, September 1978; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 8)
  - History of Funding [file 1/2], 1974-1977; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 9)
  - History of Funding [file 2/2], 1974-1977; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 10)
  - History of Membership, 1973-1977; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 11)
  - "How to Raise Money for Kids (Public and Private)", 1974; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 12)
  - Hoyes, Graves, Bailey, and Company, 1973-1977; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 13)
  - Income Statements (NCCY), 1972-1973; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 14)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1959-1973; Series 2 (Box 1579, Folder 15)
  - IRS Determination of NCOCY's Tax Status, 1973-1975; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 1)
  - IRS Form 990, 1973-1975; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 2)
  - IRS Tax Form on SEC. 501(c)(3), 1973; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 3)
  - Joint Conference on Children and Youth (Chicago, IL), 1956-1957; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Isabella, 1975-1977; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 4)
    Jones, Isabella
  - Lee, Doris May, 1959-1961; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 2)
    Lee, Doris May
  - Legislation and Notes, circa 1972; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 5)
  - LeStrange, William, 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 6)
  - Letters From Board Members, 1979; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Board Members, 1979-1980; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 8)
  - Matching Funds, 1974-1975; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 9)
  - Members (NCCY), 1968-1971; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 10)
  - Membership Campaign Description, 1977; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 11)
  - Membership Information (CNOCY), 1961-1968; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 12)
  - Minutes (CCY), 1973; Series 2 (Box 1580, Folder 13)
  - Minutes (CCY), 1974-1977; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (CCY), 1978-1980; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and Bylaws, 1951-1961; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 3)
  - Name Change, 1976; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 4)
  - Name Change and Bylaws, December 1977; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 5)
  - National Child Health Day, 1929-1930; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 3)
  - NCCY-Activities Committee, 1962; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 6)
  - NCCY-Annual Meeting, October 1965; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 7)
  - NCCY-Annual Meeting, November 1966; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 8)
  - NCCY-Annual Meeting, October 1967; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 9)
  - NCCY-Annual Meeting, November 1968; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 10)
  - NCCY-Authoring for Action, May 1972; Series 2 (Box 1581, Folder 11)
  - NCCY-Background Information, 1960; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 1)
  - NCCY-Background Material, 1965-1966; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 2)
  - NCCY-Bylaws, circa 1961; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 3)
  - NCCY-Fact Sheets, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 4)
  - NCCY-Finance Committee, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 5)
  - NCCY-Form for Organizations Wishing to Participate, circa 1970; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 6)
  - NCCY-Meetings, 1960-1965; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 7)
  - NCCY-Meetings, April 1966; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 8)
  - NCCY-Meetings, April 1969; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 9)
  - NCCY-Meetings, October 1969; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 10)
  - NCCY-Meetings, April 1970; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 11)
  - NCCY-Meetings, September 1970; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 12)
  - NCCY-Meetings, February 1971; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 13)
  - NCCY-Meetings, December 1971; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 14)
  - NCCY-Meetings, January 1972; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 15)
  - NCCY-Meetings, November 1972; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 16)
  - NCCY-Memoranda [file 1/2], 1967; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 17)
  - NCCY-Memoranda [file 2/2], 1967; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 18)
  - NCCY-Minutes, November 1972; Series 2 (Box 1582, Folder 19)
  - NCCY-Minutes, 1972-1973; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 1)
  - NCCY-Miscellaneous, 1960-1961; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 2)
  - NCCY-Note to Members on Election and Further Nominations, circa 1967; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 3)
  - NCCY-Operating Committee, 1960; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 4)
  - NCCY-Participating Organizations, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 5)
  - NCCY-Procedural Forms, 1966; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 6)
  - NCCY-Program Evaluation Meeting, August 1965; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 7)
  - NCCY-Progress Reports, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 8)
  - NCCY-Report to the Nation, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 9)
  - NCCY-Reports, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 10)
  - NCCY-Resource Material, 1966; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 11)
  - NCCY-Spring Meeting, May 1967; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 12)
  - NCCY-Spring Meeting, May 1968; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 13)
  - NCCY-Steering Committee, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 14)
  - NCCY-Training Material, 1966; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 15)
  - "NCCY Reporter", 1961-1967; Series 2 (Box 1583, Folder 16)
  - "NCCY Reporter", 1968-1971; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 1)
  - NCCY to Project Contract and Fund Transfer, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 2)
  - "A National Study of the Implementation and Implications of the SSI Program for Disabled Children", November 1976; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 3)
  - New IRS Determination, November 1973; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 4)
  - New York State Report, 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 5)
  - Nominations, 1974-1977; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 6)
  - Notice of Expiration of Lease, October 1977; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 7)
  - Officers and Board of Directors, 1973; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 8)
  - "On Teacher Quality" and "The Promotion of Quality in Teaching", 1983; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 9)
  - Organizing Project, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 10)
  - "Patterns of Organization of State Committees for Children and Youth", 1962; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 11)
  - Payment Codes, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 12)
  - Policy Statement (CCY), November 1978; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 13)
  - Profile on the Organization, circa 1978; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 14)
  - Program Committee, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 15)
  - "Program Mid-Decade Conference on Children and Youth", April 1966; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 16)
  - "Programs for Handicapped Children and How they Work Together", May 1978; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 17)
  - Progress Reports (CCY), March 1978; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 18)
  - Project-Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 19)
  - Project-Invited Organizations, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 20)
  - Project-Outlines, 1972; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 21)
  - Promissory Note, 1980; Series 2 (Box 1584, Folder 22)
  - "A Proposal for One Year Funding Support of the NCOCY", circa 1973; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 1)
  - Prospectus (CCY), March 1978; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 2)
  - Records of Address Change with Recorder of Deeds, April 1978; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 3)
  - Reorganization Idea (CCY), 1977; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 4)
  - Report of Conference, November 1979; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 5)
  - Report of Finance Committee, October 1968; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 6)
  - "The Report on the Questionnaires Submitted to National Organizations", March 1963; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 7)
  - "The Report to the Nation on Children and Youth"-Draft, 1967; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 8)
  - Sale of Stock (NCCY), 1972; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 9)
  - "Suggestions to Organizations Concerned with Conference Participation", 1958; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 10)
  - Supplement to Monograph IV, May 1932; Series 2 (Box 4062, Folder 5)
  - Tax Exempt Status Records, 1959-1960; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 11)
  - Tax Related Information, 1976; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 12)
  - Tax Returns, 1973-1975; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 13)
  - Voting Members, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 14)
  - Voting Members CCY Associate Recruitment, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 15)
  - Voting Members-Packet of Materials, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 16)
  - White House Conference-Committee on Invitations, 1958-1959; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 4)
  - White House Conference-Correspondence, 1952; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 5)
  - White House Conference-Correspondence, 1958-1960; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 6)
  - White House Conference-Membership Lists, 1959-1960; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 7)
  - White House Conference-Names, Delegates, Biographical Sketches, 1959; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 8)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1960-1969; Series 2 (Box 1516, Folder 9)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth-Planning Conference, 1969; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 17)
  - White House Conference on Education-Folder, 1955; Series 2 (Box 1517, Folder 1)
  - White House Conference on Education-Folder, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1517, Folder 2)
  - White House Conference on Education-Reports/Speeches, 1955; Series 2 (Box 1517, Folder 3)
  - White House Conference on Youth-Roster of Delegates, April 1971; Series 2 (Box 1585, Folder 18)
- Higher Education Council, 1970-1983; Series 3; 0.5 Linear Feet
  The Higher Education Council was established in 1974 to provide an identity for higher education within NEA and to guarantee higher education faculty a formal channel through which to voice their concerns to key Association decision-makers and staff.
  The council was a 13-member elected body where each member serves a two year term.
  This series contains materials created by the Higher Education Council. The files include final reports from various committees created by the council to investigate issues of the day.
  Education, Higher -- United States
  - "The 1983 National Education Association Higher Education Conference", Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 4)
  - "Agreement Between Massachusetts Society of Professors and Massachusetts Teachers Association at Lowell Technological Institute and Board of Trustees of Lowell Technological Institute", circa 1973; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 5)
  - "Dushane Fund", 1973; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 6)
  - Higher Education Council Meeting Minutes, March 6 1980 - March 7 1980; series 3 (Box 4494, Folder 17)
  - "Higher Education, A Source Book for NEA Leaders" [file 1/2], October 1973; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 7)
  - "Higher Education, A Source Book for NEA Leaders" [file 2/2], October 1973; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 8)
  - "Higher Education in the United States: An Overview", circa 1974; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 9)
  - National Council for Higher Education News, 1988-1991; series 3 (Box 4297, Folder 23)
  - "National Education Association", 1972; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 10)
  - "National Education Association Member Services Catalog for Higher Education", circa 1970; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 11)
  - "National Higher Education Association", circa 1972; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 12)
  - "NEA Higher Education is Near You!", 1972; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 13)
  - "Negotiate", 1972; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 14)
  - The Politics of Remedy: State Legislative Views on Higher Education, January 1996; Series 3 (Box 4095, Folder 3)
  - Press Release, 1978; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 15)
  - To Promote Academic Justice and Excellence: Information Technology: A Road to the Future, 1995; Series 3 (Box 4095, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations, circa 1981; Series 3 (Box 1517, Folder 16)
  - Reports, 1978-1980; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 1)
  - Special Features: Excellence in Affairs of Higher Education, undated; Series 3 (Box 4062, Folder 6)
  - "Tell This", 1973; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 2)
  - "What to do in a Membership Campaign", 1973; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 3)
  - "Who is the Real you?", 1973; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 4)
  - "You and Higher Education Legislation", 1972; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 5)
  - "You Owe it to Yourself", 1973; Series 3 (Box 1518, Folder 6)
- National Council of Education, 1849-1942; Series 4; 0.75 Linear Feet
  The National Council of Education (NCE) was created in 1881 at a meeting of the National Department of Superintendence in Washington, DC. The council was to discuss, define and state with accuracy the different views and theories about educational issues and to discover and represent the basis for such theories and viewpoints. The insights and discussions would be relayed in an annual report to the NEA.
  The NCE also held the power to create committees to further explore issues in depth, and report back to the main council.
  This series contains materials created by the National Council of Education. The files include reports created by the council or subcommittees, as well as historical notes on the Council itself and recommendations concerning the role of education should play in the civic and social life of Americans.
  - Anniversary Dinner (Columbus, OH), 1930; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 7)
  - A Review of Certain Studies of Activities, Abilities, and Traits of Citizens, prepared for use by the Committee on Objectives in Education, 1930; Series 4
  - "Committee on Industrial Education in Schools for Rural Communities", 1905-1908; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Resolutions, June 1934; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 9)
  - Descriptions (Xeroxes), March 1922; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 10)
  - Education and Training, September 1931; series 4 (Box 4332, Folder 1)
  - "Final Report of the Committee on Rural Education", July 1923; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 11)
  - "Final Report of the Committee on Rural Education", July, 1923; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 4)
  - "Final Report of the Committee on Uniform Records and Reports", February 1912; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 12)
  - Four Pamphlets, 1933, 1943; series 4 (Box 4322, Folder 2)
  - Historical Notes Prepared on the Occasion of the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Council at Columbus, Ohio, June 28-30, 1930, December, 1930; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 5)
  - History (Xeroxes), 1914-1920; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 13)
  - Magazines, 1932-1942; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 14)
  - NEA Retirement Benefits Forum 2007, 2007 November 7 - 9; Series 4 (Box 4969, Folder 8)
  - NEA Retirement & Benefits Forum Speaker Presentations, 2007; Series 4 (Box 4969, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlet [Historical Statement, Constitution, & Officers], June, 1930; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 6)
  - [Programs for Meetings & Dinners], 1930-1942; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 7)
  - Pupil Personnel in Part-Time Schools: A study of the Social Composition, Educational Status, & Current Working Conditions of Part-Time School Pupils, July, 1926; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 8)
  - "Report of the Committee on County Superintendent's Problems", July 1922; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 15)
  - Report of the Commitee on Industrial Education in Schools for Rural Communities, July, 1905; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 9)
  - "Report of the Committee on the Relations of Public Libraries to Public Schools", 1899; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 16)
  - "Report of the Committee on Taxation as Related to Public Education", July 1905; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 17)
  - "Report of the Committee on the Teaching of Democracy", February 1923; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 18)
  - Three Pamphlets (Freedom, Freedom in Teaching, NEA Institute), February 1932; series 4 (Box 4322, Folder 3)
  - Transcript, July 1923; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 19)
  - Two Pamphlets (Freedom, Social Planning, and Leadership; Discussion), 1932; series 4 (Box 4322, Folder 4)
  - What are the Major Objectives of Education?, 1931; Series 4 (Box 4421, Folder 10)
  - "What the High Schools Ought to Teach", 1940; Series 4 (Box 1518, Folder 20)
- Council on Instruction, 1959-1962; Series 5; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Biographical / Historical
  The Council is broadly representative of the united teaching profession and serves as an advisory group to NEA governing bodies and to the NEA Instruction and Professional Development staff. Council members, who are appolntd by the NEA president for three-year terms, provide IPD staff a continuing dialogue with practitioners.
  Scope and Contents
  Series contains material created by or on behalf of the Council.
  - How Good Are Your Schools?, 1959; series 5 (Box 4322, Folder 5)
  - Toward Better Evaluation of Learning...a Brief Guide for Teachers and Administrators and Others Concerned with Testing and Evaluation in Our Schools, 1962; series 5 (Box 4322, Folder 6)
- National Council on Teacher Retirement, 1926-1974; series 6; 2.5 Linear Feet
  Biographical/ Historical note
  In 1911, a Committee on Teachers' Salaries, Tenure, and Pensions was appointed. Under various titles, committees worked on retirment problems until 1936, when the Committee on Retirment Allowances was merged with the National Council of Retirment Systems to form the present Council.
  The Council is a workshop-type NEA unit in which executive officers and trustee members of state and local teacher retirement systems may put before teachers the technical problems of operating retirment systems and teachers may put before administrators their problems of retirment security.
  The Council objective, in general, is to improve the economic status of teachers through safeguarding and strengthening legal provisions for retirment income of teachers, that teachers may be freed from fear of insecurity after retirment.
  Source: NEA Handbook for Local, State, and National Associations 1969-1970
  Series contains material created or held by the Council. Besides records of Council meetings, the series contains summaries of existing retirement and pension plans for comparative and analytical purposes.
  - 1969 Teacher Retirement System Summaries, 1966; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 7)
  - Advocations of Retired Teachers, April 1941; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 8)
  - Analysis of Local Provisions for Teacher Retirement, January 1947; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 9)
  - Analysis of the Statutory Provisions for State Teachers Retirement Systems, January 1939; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Retirement Allowances: Teacher Retirment Legislation in 1934 and 1935 to Date, July 1935; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 11)
  - A Decade of Court Decisions on Teacher Retirment 1930-1939, 1940-1949, 1950-1959, 1940-1960; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 12)
  - How to Establish a Sound Teachers' Retirement System: Report of Publications Committee National Council on Teacher Retirement of the NEA Atlantic City Meeting, 1943; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 13)
  - How to Provide Reciprocity in Teacher Retirement, January 1951; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 14)
  - The Migration of Public-School Teachers: Its Scope and Direction, Its Significance for State Teacher Retirement Systems, February 1949; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 15)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 1/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4322, Folder 16)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 2/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4323, Folder 1)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 3/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4323, Folder 2)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 4/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4323, Folder 3)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 5/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4323, Folder 4)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 6/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4324, Folder 1)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 7/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4324, Folder 2)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 8/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4324, Folder 3)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 9/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4324, Folder 4)
  - The National Council of Teachers' Retirement Systems Proceedings of the Annual Meeting [file 10/10], 1926-1974; series 6 (Box 4324, Folder 5)
  - Preliminar Report Concerning Establishment of Retirement System for Headquarters Staff of NEA: Prepared Under the Instructions of the Committee on Salaries and Salary Increases, February 1927; series 6 (Box 4325, Folder 1)
  - Public Retirement Systems, 1955-1959; series 6 (Box 4325, Folder 2)
  - Recent Happenings in Social Security, February 1952; series 6 (Box 4325, Folder 3)